A Finding Aid to the Gustave Harrow legal records relating to the Estate of Mark Rothko AAA.harrgust2
Archives of American Art
- Appeals Documents, 1972-1979; Series 4; 4.3 Linear feet Boxes 26-31
  - M Files - Construction Proceeding - Motion for Leave to Appeal, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - M Files - Construction Proceeding - Motion to Terminate Control of Clerk, 1974-1975 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - M Files - Construction Proceeding - Fees, 1975-1979 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - M Files - Election Proceeding - Motin to Refer to Midonick, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - M Files - Motion to Deliver Paintings to Warehouse, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - M Files - Appendix of Respondent-Appellant, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - M Files - Joint Appendix...Herbert Ferber...Will of Mary Alice Rothko, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - M Files - Motion for Protective Order - AG Interr. I, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - M Files - Motion for Protective Order - To Strike Interrog. I, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - M Files - Motion for Appendix, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - M Files - Motion for Protective Order to Strike Interrog. II, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - M Files - Foundation's Motion to Dismiss AG for Protective Order - EBT of Foundation Directors, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - M Files - Marlborough's Motion to Dismiss AG for Protective Order re EBT of Foundation DIrectors, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - M Files - Motion to Stay Order Directing Foundation Directors' EBTs Pending Appeal, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - M Files - Motion to Dismiss Foundation's Appeal, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - M Files - Appellate's Appendix, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - M Files - Motion to Sever, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - M Files - Motion for Time to Objet to Interrog., 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - M Files - Motion to Fix Date for Lloyd's EBT, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - M Files - Motion to Strike Answers to hold Marlborough in Contempt, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - M Files - Post-Trial Memorandum of Marlborough Gallery, Inc. & Marlborough A.G. etc., 1973-1975 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - M Files - Motion for Leave to Appeal to Court of Appeals - AG Protective Order, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - M Files - Motion for Stay of Order to Compel Answers (Purchasers' Names), 1973 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - M Files - Motion for Referee, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - M Files - Motion for Levine Protective Order, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - M Files - Motion for Disclosure Proceeding - N.Y. Times Article, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - M Files - Motion to Fix a Trial Date and to Conclude Discovery, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - M Files - Motion to Examine Non-Party Witness, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - M Files - Motion to Strike MAG Interrog., 1973 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - M Files - Motion to Strike Interr. & Contempt II, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - M Files - Motion for Levine Protective Order, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - M Files - Motion Opposing Discovery Reis & Stamos, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - M Files - Motion to Terminate EBTs, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - M Files - Motion to Take Depositions of R, S & L, Bial, Schwartz, Swetlitz & Kozac, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - M Files - Motion - Discovery Notices, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - M Files - Motion for EBT of MNY Employees, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - M Files - Motion to Transfer Custody of an Exhibit, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - M Files - Motion to Conclude Reis EBT, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - M Files - Motion for Swetlitz EBT, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - M Files - Motion for a Protective Order against Northrup Interrog., 1973 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - M Files - Inspection of Paintings, 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - M Files - Motion for Review, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - M Files - Motion to Quash Subpoenas, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - M Files - Motion to Impound, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - M Files - Motion to Hold Marlborough in Contempt, 1974-1975 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - M Files - Motion for Ritter & Beck EBT, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - M Files - MOMA Proceeding, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - M Files - Motion to Dismiss Executors re: Tax Assessments, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - M Files - Libel Action - Confidentiality of Pre-Trial Briefs, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - M Files - AG Motion for New Evidence, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - M Files - Motion for Restraint - R,S & L, Lloyd & Marlborough, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - M Files - Motion for Restraint - Lloyd & Marlborough, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - M Files - Decree & Motion for Administration, 1975-1976 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - M Files - Toronto - Restraining Order, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - M Files - Motion to Reargue Return of Paintings, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - M Files - Motion for Marlborough's Records, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - M Files - Motion Res. for Stay of Enforcement of Decretal Paragraphs, 1975-1976 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - M Files - Motion to Punish Marlborough for Contempt - Shipment of 6 more Pictures Modification, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - M Files - Motion Levine for Stay Without Bond Pending Determination of Appeal, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - M Files - Motion - Marlborough's to Hold AG in Contempt, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - M Files - Motion for Marlborough to Report Sales, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - M Files - Motion for Marlborough's Records (2) to Modify Stay of Enforcement, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - M Files - Decree - Appeal, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - M Files - Motion to Strike AG Motion for Stay of Enforcement, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - M Files - Motion to Reargue Orders Granting Stays, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - M Files - Motion - Lloyd & Marlborough for Stay of Enforcement of Money Judgement Pending Appeal, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - M Files - Motion for Permission to Appeal Orders, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - M Files - Bond, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - M Files - Accounting Proceedure, 1976-1978 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - M Files - Motion to Reargue Marlborough Reporting Sales, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - M Files - Prizel v. Karelsen & Saidenberg, 1976-1978 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - M Files - Motion to Determine Value of 658 Pictures, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - M Files - Levine's Motion "New Evidence", 1976 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - M Files - Motion to Extend Time for R&S to Perfect Appeal - Cross-Motion to Modify Stays, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - M Files - Motion for Marlborough Contempt, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - M Files - Motion for Lloyd Protective Order, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 42)
  - M Files - Motion to Perfect AG Appeal - Filing Part of Record, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - M Files - Accounting Proceedure Reis Protective Order, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 44)
  - M Files - Motions to Extend Stay of Enforcement of Money Judg. - R,S&L Cross-Motion - AG as to Time for Filing Appendices & Points, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 45)
  - M Files - Foundation Proceeding Supreme Court, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 46-47)
  - M Files - Motion to Reject Appendices or Dismiss Appeals unless Proper Appendices are Filed & to Extend Time to File Respondent's Points, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - M Files - Guggenheim Exhibits, 1976-1977 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - M Files - Appeal to Court of Appeals from Decretal Paragraph 26 Denying AG Motion to Reopen Record, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - M Files - Motion for Levine to Appeal to Court of Appeals for Relief, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - M Files - Accounting Procedure - Levine Protective Order, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - M Files - Accounting Proceeding Stamos Protective Order, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - M Files - Fees - Restraining Order & Examinations of R,S & L, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - M Files - Reis Bankruptcy, 1974-1978 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - M Files - Motion to Modify Stay in Bankruptcy Case, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - M Files - Pace Contract, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - M Files - Greenspan v. Foundation, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - M Files - Enforcement of Decree, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - M Files - Fees & 3-33, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - M Files - Eisenberg v. Rothko, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - M Files - Fees, 1974, 1977-1979 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - M Files - Estate (Bankruptcy) Reis v. Karelsen - Olick...James Hefferman; Irene Warehauer, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - M Files - Karelsen v. James, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Deposition of Gerald Dickler, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 18-19)
  - Deposition of Frank Karelsen, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Deposition of Plaut, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Deposition of Kate Rothko Prizel, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - (Construction) Deposition of Bernard J. Reis, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
  - Deposition of Saidenberg Gallery, Inc. by Eleanor B. Saidenberg, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Deposition of Daniel Saidenberg, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
  - Appendix of Petitioner-Respondents, undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Appendix of Respondents-Appellants Vol I of II, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Appendix of Respondents-Appellants Vol II of II, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Appendix of Respondents Appellants, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Brief for Attorney General, Cross-Petitioner-Respondent, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Brief of Attorney General-Cross-Petitioner-Appelant, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Brief of Attorney General, Cross-Petitioner-Respondent (Appeal from Order Directing Disclosure), 1973 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Brief of...Barbara B. Northrup on Appeal from Orders Denying Mtoions for Protective Orders and Compelling Answers to Interrogatories, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Reply Brief and Supplemental Appendix of Appellants Stamos and Reis, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Brief in Behalf of Petitioner-Respondent Kate Rothko, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Appendix to Reply Brief of Marlborough Gallery, Marlborough A.G. and Francis K. Lloyd, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Record on Appeal of Attorney General, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Record on Appeal, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Brief on Cross-Appeal of Attorney General, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Answering Brief of Attorney General (In Answer to Main Brief of Appellants J. Russell Rogerson et al), 1972 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Reply Brief on Cross-Appeal of Attorney General (In Response to Manufacturers' Answering Brief) [Gebbie], 1972 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Petition to Set Aside Directors of Mark Rothko Foundation, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Case and Post-Trial files, 1972-1984; Series 5; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 31-32
  Arranged alphabetically by subject
  Series 5 is comprised of post-trial files and other miscellaneous materials related to the case. Included are notes, clippings, correspondence, documents on fee arrangements, legal documents, and documents gathered together for the BBC documentary "The Rothko Conspiracy."
  - BBC, 1972-1979 (Box 31, Folder 6-7)
  - Breed - Abbott Memo on Conduct of Trial, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Damage Amounts, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Determination of Attorney's Fees, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 10-12)
  - Reis & Attorney's Fees etc., 1971-1977 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Fees, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Gebbie Foundation - Post-Trial Memorandum of Attorney General, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence & Articles about Rothko Case, 1978-1981 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Index - Reis & Stamos, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Indices - Various, 1972-1973, undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Internal Index to Files, 1972-1977, undated (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - IRS Notes, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Kavelson, 1973-1974 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Lloyd - Prosecution - D.A. & Marlborough, 1977-1983 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - People of State of New York against Francis K. Lloyd - Transcript, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Lloyd's Conviction, 1982-1983 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Notes & Miscellaneous, 1975-1979 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Notes for Files re Manual, 1974-1979 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Rothko Estate Miscellaneous 1982-1984 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Rothko Estate - Decree, 1978-1981 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - N.J. - Rothkos - Lloyd, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Recent Info as to Pictures, 1979-1981 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Return and Movement of Pictures, 1978-1981 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Returned Paintings & Computation of Damages, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Rothko Distribution - Diary & Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Settlement Proposal - Dickler, Paul Weis, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Settling Transcript - Sept 76 - no moe corrections to transcripts, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Severence of Trial Issues - Notes, 1972, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Stamos & Levine - Estate - Foundation Accounting?, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Subs., Sales - Misc., 1974 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Telephone Numbers & Addresses - Rothko, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Testimony on 5-8-72 - L, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Trust & Estates - General, 1972-1976 (Box 32, Folder 20)
- Reference Materials, Notes, and Writings, 1970-1986; Series 6; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 32-33
  Series 6 contains clippings, correspondence, notes, and Gustave Harrow writings about the trial, including articles and a book entitled Art, the Artist, and the Consequences of Rothko: Lasting Legal Impressions from the Estate of a Great Artist.
  - Book on Ethics - Rothko Source Material for Background, 1972-1974, undated (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Clippings 1 and 2, 1971-1974 (Box 32, Folder 22-23)
  - Clippings [Loose between 2 and 3], 1974-1977 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Clippings 3, 1976-1979 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Clippings 4 and 5, 1975-1977 (Box 32, Folder 26-27)
  - Clippings - American Lawyer, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Clippings - Art Worker's News, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Clippings - Christian Science Monitor, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Clippings - Daily News, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Clippings - Globe and Mail, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - Clippings - International Herald Tribune, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - Clippings - Knickerbocker News, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - Clippings - New York Law, 1972-1976 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - Clippings - New York Magazine, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - Clippings - New York Post, 1975-1977 (Box 32, Folder 37)
  - Clippings - New York Times, 1971, 1972, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 38-40)
  - Clippings - New York Times, 1974-1979 (Box 33, Folder 1-6)
  - Clippings - Newsday (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Clippings - The Sunday Sun, Baltimore MD - Spectator, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Clippings - The Village Voice, 1974-1976 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Magazine Articles, 1970-1983 (Box 33, Folder 10-11)
  - MRF - Rothko (Ferber), 1986 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Notes and Correspondence for Articles, 1972-1977 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Shapiro, Meyer, 1964, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Writings by and about Harrow, 1978-1982 (Box 33, Folder 15)
- Metropolitan Museum of Art / Annenberg Etc., 1971-1981; Series 7; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 33-35
  Arranged in original order
  Found here are reference materials assembled by Harrow for legal actions unrelated to the Rothko case. They include his researchabout the proposed Walter Annenberg gift of a communications center to the Metropolitan Museum of Art in 1976. Included are clippings and articles, Metropolitan Museum reports, notes, correspondence, and one sound cassette recording of the 3/14/1977 Metropolitan Museum of Art Board Meeting. The remainder of the materials concern various other issues at the museum, including administrative issues, challenges to the authenticity of certain pieces, the de Groot donation, the Packard Collection, and alleged misattributions in an Asian Art exhibition.
  - Charlotte Devree [Executive Committee representative], 1977 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Executive Committee - Devree, 1977-1979 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - From Devree, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - From Devree - Excerpts [Meetings], 1977 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Ex-Officio Reps (Morgan) 6/77 Exec. Comm., 1977 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - From Goldsmith, 1976-1978 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - From Manhattan Bd. Annenberg - Mets Docs of 3/14/77 Hearing, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Material from Annenberg, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Mets. Memos - Annenberg, 1976-1977 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Met. Misc. Annenberg - Pd. Press, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Conferences, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Diary & Misc. Correspondence, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Memos, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Notes, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - Annenberg - Met press 1, 1976-1977 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - Annenberg - Met Press 2, 1976-1977 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Press, 1973-1977 (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
  - From Redman, Roland, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    Contains Sony C60 sound cassette of 3.14.77 Board Hearing - Met Gilpatric
  - Hoving, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Mets Docs from Manhattan BD. Hearing 3-14-77, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Met Constitution & By-Laws, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Names & Appointments Met, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Met Annual Report 1977 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Met Annual Report 1979 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - American Bicentennial Wing of the Metropolitan Museum of Art 1976 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art Master Plan Report July 15, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Met - The Second Century - The Comprehensive Architectural Plan for the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - De Groot Estate, 1972-1973 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - De Groot Fund, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Muscarella - Met, 1976-1978 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Packard, 1977-1979 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Copies of Fong Chow's File 1 - Li Ch'eng Painting - Wintry Forest, 1972-1973 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Copies of Fong Chow's File 2 - Shih Toa Painting - Album 1972 - from Cheng Dai - Chien, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Copies of Fong Chow's File 3 - Gift of Catalogue - 1976 - from Wen Fong, undated (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Copies of Fong Chow's File 4 - Shih Chi Painting - 1973, undated (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Copies of Fong Chow's File 5 - Han Kan Painting - 1977 - Dillon Fund, undated (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Copies of Fong Chow's File 6 3 Paintings - Purchase from P.B., 1976 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Copies of Fong Chow's File 7 - 3 Vases - 1972 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Copies of Fong Chow Files 8 - Packard - 1975, 1975-1976 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Copies of Fong Chow's Files 9 - The "25" Paintings - C.C. Wang, 1975-1976 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Copies of Fong Chow's Files 10 - Cloister Piece, undated (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Packard - Nov 10, 1977 - FF (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Fong Chow 12/21/79 - 2 Pix (+ 1 Pic), 1972-1979 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Packard 1, 1975-1976 (Box 34, Folder 30-37)
  - Incense Burner (Jade) & F.C. Misc, 1978-1979 (Box 34, Folder 38-39)
  - Met - Packard - Lee, 1975-1977 (Box 34, Folder 40)
  - 1 Packard (Lee) Documents, undated (Box 34, Folder 41)
  - 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 Packard (Lee) Notes, 1974-1976, undated (Box 34, Folder 42-48)
  - The "25" Lee, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 49)
  - Copies of Lee's File on Packard 1 Documents, undated (Box 34, Folder 50)
  - Copies of Lee's File on Packard 2, 3 Notes, undated (Box 34, Folder 51-52)
  - Copies of Lee's File on Packard 4,5 Notes, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
  - Copies of Lee's File on Packard 6 Photo, Estimates & Notes, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Copies of Lee's File on Packard 7 Estimates, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Copies of Lee's File on Packard 8 Notes, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Sackler Wing, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Paid Press etc. & Misc. & General, 1977-1979 (Box 35, Folder 7-8)